(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-23T20:25:59.531744",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
これは、もうひとつの物語。
This is another story.
SPECIAL OPENING ACT
諸君！カレーメシは好きか？
Attention! Do you like Curry Meshi?
わたしは
I...
カレーメシが大好きだ
...love Curry Meshi!
カレーメシが好きだ
I like Curry Meshi,
ハヤシメシも好きだ
Hayashi Meshi too,
キーマカレーメシも好きだ
Keema Curry Meshi,
カレーメシシーフードも好きだ
Seafood Curry Meshi,
ウーマーメシも好きだ
U-ma Meshi too,
オシャメシも好きだ
and Osha Meshi!
日本で一番カレーメシが大好きだ！
I love Curry Meshi more than anything in Japan!
街中で
In the city,
森林で
in the forest,
公園で
in the park,
山頂で
on the mountaintop,
食卓で
at the dining table,
部屋で
in the room,
学校で
at school,
職場でにこやかに
cheerfully at work...
お湯かけ5分でいつでもどこでもおいしいカレーが楽しめる
Pour hot water for 5 minutes, and enjoy delicious curry anywhere, anytime!
世界で一番カレーメシが大好きだ！
I love Curry Meshi most in the world!
諸君もカレーメシが大好きならば、会場を黄金に染めてくれ！
If you all love Curry Meshi too, paint this venue in gold!
さあ諸君、スパイスラボの登場だ！
Now everyone, behold the arrival of Spice Lab!
お湯を入れて 待て 5分待て
Pour hot water, wait, wait 5 minutes,
お湯を混ぜろ 混ぜろ 混ぜて溶けたらカレーがドドーン
stir and mix, once melted, boom goes the curry!
カレーカレー カレーカレー カレーにしよ
Curry, curry, curry, curry, let's make it curry!
腹ペコ カレーが食べたい でも配信直前
Starving, I want to eat curry, but stream is right before us.
これなんて大ピンチ 助けて
What a huge pinch, help me!
そんな私に救世主 登場 まじで？
A savior appears for someone like me—seriously?
黄色なあいつが黄色さ
That yellow fellow is all yellow!
カレーカレー カレーカレー カレーにしよ
Curry, curry, curry, curry, let's make it curry!
お湯を入れて たった5分で
Pour hot water, in just 5 minutes,
本当に 本当に カレーなんて作れるの？
can you really, really make curry like that?
フタを開けて シャバシャバでも 大丈夫
Open the lid, watery is fine too,
混ぜろ 混ぜろ ひたすら混ぜろ 混ぜろ 混ぜろ
stir, stir, stir endlessly, mix and stir!
いつさ ミラクル くるくるくるに
Anytime, a miracle spins and spins,
新しい カレーメシ
into a brand new Curry Meshi!
Lets! ミラクル くるくるくるお
Let's! Miracle spinning around,
新しい カレーの真時代
the new true era of curry!
スパイス詰めこんだ こだわりの味
Packed with spices, a flavor crafted with care,
大満足 刹那火でしょ
thoroughly satisfying in a flash!
新生 カレーメシ
Reborn Curry Meshi!
しゅばっと作れて美味いっすな！
It's so fast and easy to make, delicious!
カレーでこういうことびこよ
That's what we call curry wonder!
普通に美味しいよ
It's just genuinely delicious!
実績とは思えないほどコクのある旨み踏み踏み
With umami so rich you wouldn't believe its track record, stepping right along,
あっちのバリエーションも豊富だからいつまでも無限にいけちゃう
variations over there are so abundant you can keep going endlessly!
カレーカレー カレーカレー カレーにしよ
Curry, curry, curry, curry, let's make it curry!
電子レンジも お鍋もいらない
No microwave, no pot needed,
本当に 本当に お湯だけ入れれば大丈夫
really, really, just hot water is all you need!
即席食品の てっぺんめざし
Aiming for the peak of instant foods,
混ぜろ 混ぜろ ひたすら混ぜろ 混ぜろ 混ぜろ
stir, stir, stir endlessly, mix and stir!
まだの時代がキタァ！
The era we've been waiting for is here!
いつさ ミラクル くるくるくるに
Anytime, a miracle spins and spins,
新しい カレーメシ
into a brand new Curry Meshi!
Lets! ミラクル くるくるくるさいこー
Let's! Miracle spinning around, awesome!
感じちゃう キミンライ
You can feel it, your future,
玉ねぎの旨み 確信的な
onion umami, convincingly...
止まらない 美味しさが
unstoppable deliciousness!
新生 カレーメシ
Reborn Curry Meshi!
最先端のカレーでGO！
Go with cutting-edge curry!
さあさ ミラクル くるくるくるに
Now, now, a miracle spins and spins,
新しい カレーメシ
into a brand new Curry Meshi!
もっと ミラクル くるくるくるくるかー
More miracle, spinning around and around,
いただきます！
Let's dig in!
いつさ ミラクル くるくるくるに
Anytime, a miracle spins and spins,
新しい カレーメシ
into a brand new Curry Meshi!
Lets! ミラクル くるくるくるくるおーい！
Let's! Miracle spinning around and around, hey!
お湯を入れて 秘伝のルーを
Add hot water and mix in the secret roux,
混ぜろ 混ぜて溶けたらカレーがドーン!
mix it, and once it melts, curry goes boom!
カレー・カレー・カレー・カレー
Curry, curry, curry, curry,
カレーメシで show!
Curry Meshi show!
カレー・カレー・カレー・カレー
Curry, curry, curry, curry,
カレーメシで show!
Curry Meshi show!
カレー・カレー・カレー・カレー
Curry, curry, curry, curry,
カレーメシで show!
Curry Meshi show!
日清カレーメシ
Nissin Curry Meshi!
カレー・カレー・カレー・カレー カレーメシで show!
Curry, curry, curry, curry, Curry Meshi show!
皆さん、こんにちはー！
Hello everyone!
こんにちはー！
Hello!
たくさんのお客さんが来てる！うれしい！
So many people came! I'm so happy!
ねえ、本当にすごいってば！
Hey, it's seriously amazing!
みんな来てくれてありがとうー！
Thank you everyone for coming!
満員だよ！
It's packed!
すごーい！
Amazing!
さあ、ということで カレーメシ イン アニメロ サマー ライブ
Now then, the song we performed for Curry Meshi in Animelo Summer Live
披露させていただいたのは 日清カレーメシとホロライブのコラボレーションオリジナル楽曲
was an original collaboration song between Nissin Curry Meshi and Hololive,
「カレーメシ イン ミラクル」でした！
"Curry Meshi in Miracle"!
はーい！
Yay!
お湯かけごはんで
With hot water on rice,
いつでもどこでも！
anytime, anywhere!
美味しいカレーが楽しめる！日清カレーメシさんの提供でお届けする
Delicious curry you can enjoy anytime, anywhere! Brought to you by Nissin Curry Meshi,
こちらのスペシャルオープニングアクトを務めさせていただくのは、
serving as this special opening act
バーチャル事務所ホロライブ所属 カレーメシコラボレーションユニット「スパイスラブ」です！
is Spice Love, the Curry Meshi collaboration unit from the virtual agency Hololive!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
We look forward to working with you!
よろしくお願いしまーす！よろしくお願いしまーす！
今日は日清カレーメシさんからのミッションで、このさいたまスーパーアリーナを温めにきちゃいましたー！
Today, on a mission from Nissin Curry Meshi, we came to warm up Saitama Super Arena!
いぇーい！いぇーい！ねえ、本当にすごいってば！
Yay! Seriously, it's amazing!
まさか、アニさまの初日、たくさんのアーティストさんに先がけて、なんとトップバッターいただきましたー！
To think, on the very first day of Animelo, ahead of so many artists, we got to be the opening act!
いや、これも日清カレーメシさんやホロライブを応援してくれるみんなのおかげでこのステージに立つことができたってば！本当に会場広えってばね！
This was all thanks to everyone supporting Nissin Curry Meshi and Hololive that we could stand on this stage! The venue is really huge!
やばいよねマジで！
It's seriously crazy!
ここにこれだけの人が集まるって本当にすごいことなんだなって改めて感じるよね。
It makes me realize once again how amazing it is for so many people to gather here.
はい、ということでホロライブをご存知でないお客様もいると思うので、自己紹介したいと思います！
So, since there might be customers here who aren't familiar with Hololive, we'd like to introduce ourselves!
みんな準備いいですかー？
Are you all ready?
いっちゃいます！ホロライブ所属スパイクラブの黄色担当、大空スパー！今日はよろしくお願いします！
Here we go! I'm Subaru Ozora, yellow representative of Hololive's Spice Love! Nice to meet you today!
はい！みなさんどうもこんこー！ホロライブ所属スパイクラブのピンク担当、湊あくあでーす！
Hi everyone, hello! I'm Aqua Minato, pink representative of Hololive's Spice Love!
かんぺこかんぺこかんぺこー！ホロライブ所属スパイクラブのブルー担当、兎田ぺこらぺこー！
pekopeko! I'm Pekora Usada, blue representative of Hololive's Spice Love!
はい！久しぶりに揃ったスパイクラブの3人が務めるこのスペシャルオープニングアクトでは、豪華なカレーメシライブステージを背景にお届けしていきます！
Yes! For this special opening act by the three members of Spice Love gathered together after a long time, we'll be bringing you a gorgeous Curry Meshi live stage in the background!
ということでね、知ってる人は知ってる！スバルが考案したスパイクラブの決めポーズ、やっときますか？
So, for those who know, shall we do the special pose devised by Subaru for Spice Love?
あの例のあれぺこですね？ 2年ぶりだよ、2年ぶり！
That famous pose, right? It's been two years!
そうだよね！またビシッと決めていきたいと思います！
That's right! Let's nail it firmly!
ぺこらさんもね、準備お願いします！
Pekora-san, please get ready too!
せーの！スパイスラバーーー！！
Ready, set! Spice Love!!
カメラさんちゃんと撮れてますか、これ？
Camera-san, are you getting this properly?
やっぱこれ揃うといいよね、可愛い！ 3人の色合いが綺麗ぺこだからね。
It looks so good when we're all together, so cute! Because our color palette is pretty.
スパイスライブでお披露目して以来だから、やっぱ嬉しいよね、なんか揃うと。
Since we debuted at Spice Live, it feels so nice to be together again.
はい！そんなこんなで日神カレーメシさんとはいろいろコラボレーションさせていただいております！
Yes! And so, we've collaborated with Nissin Curry Meshi in various ways!
改めて、先ほど披露させていただいたのは日神カレーメシとホロライブのコラボレーションオリジナル楽曲「カレーメシ・イン・ミラクル」でした！
Once again, the song we performed earlier was 'Curry Meshi in Miracle', an original collaboration song between Nissin Curry Meshi and Hololive!
昨年の2021年には地上波のゴールデンタイムで日神カレーメシとホロライブによるコラボレーションCMの...
Last year in 2021, during prime time on terrestrial television, a collaboration commercial by Nissin Curry Meshi and Hololive...
1曲目としても使用されたぺこーん！
Which was also used as our first song, peko!
日清カレーメシは、お湯をかけて5分待つだけで、いつでもどこでも美味しいカレーを食べることができてぇ！
Nissin Curry Meshi lets you enjoy delicious curry anytime, anywhere by just adding hot water and waiting 5 minutes!
ライブの前とかに栄養補給とか、ライブの後でも、あー作たくないなーってまったとき、食べに行くのもめんどくってなったときぴったりです！
It's perfect for refueling before a live show, or when you don't feel like cooking or going out to eat after one!
うん！
Yeah!
会場に来てくれたみんなも、このあとのライブをめいいっぱい楽しんだあとは、
And for everyone who came to the venue, after enjoying the rest of the live show to the fullest,
埼玉のスーパーアリーナ近くのコンビニで、絶賛発売中なので、日清カレーメシを食べながら、今日のことを振り返ってほしいぺこーん！
they're on sale right now at convenience stores near Saitama Super Arena, so we hope you'll eat some Nissin Curry Meshi and look back on today, peko!
日清カレーメシはバリエーションも豊富！見かけたら是非いろんな味をね、楽しんでほしいです。
Nissin Curry Meshi also comes in a wide variety of flavors! If you see it, we hope you'll try out all the different flavors.
今日のライブが終わったらぜひ、お買い求めください！
Be sure to grab some once today's live show is over!
はい。
Right.
ということで、せっかくなので、みんなに質問です。
So, since we have the chance, we have a question for everyone.
おお？
Oh?
ライブが終わったらカレーメシ食べてみようかなって人は、カレー色のペンライトを振ってほしいんだけど、いいですかー！
If you're thinking of eating Curry Meshi after the live show, wave your curry-colored penlights, okay?!
よーし、じゃあ、みんなに質問するぞ。
All right, then, I have a question for everyone.
ライブが終わったら、カレーメシ食べたくなったかなー？
Did you get a craving for Curry Meshi after the live show?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ということで、スパルタツの時間も残すところわずかあっという間でしたが、兄さま本番前にこの曲を聞いてください！
And with that, there's only a little time left for Spartan time—it went by in a flash, but brother, please listen to this song before the main show!
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to see the same future.
あの夢手にしたい
I want to make that dream mine.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo
Running with our different hearts, go!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
Sprouting in a pitch-black place no matter where I looked,
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
my eyes were stolen by just a tiny hope.
不安で揺るる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning my anxious, wavering heart just right,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I was mustering up just a tiny bit of courage.
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting the word "give up" and moving forward,
苦しいときももう私はひとりじゃないから
even when it's tough, I'm no longer alone.
だからもっと夢追いかけたいワクワク止まらない
That's why I want to chase my dreams more, the excitement won't stop.
想像越えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that surpasses imagination.
アクセスしてみたい後悔なんてそうさせない
I want to access it, I won't let you regret a thing.
それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
Coloring with our different hearts,
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
the dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たことのない光をリアルに届けるよ
deliver an unseen light to reality.
いつも聴こえるエールはここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers I always hear right here,
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
it makes me want to search for a new light once more.
君の笑顔は保存して進む悲しいときに読み返すよ
Saving your smile as I move forward, I'll look back at it when I'm sad,
力が湧くから胸張って夢追いかけたい
because it gives me strength; I want to hold my head high and chase my dreams.
奇跡のストーリー一緒に作ろう
Let's create a miraculous story together.
終わらない夢を誰一人欠かせない
An endless dream where not a single person can be missed.
愛が舞ったこの世界それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
In this world where love danced, color it with our different hearts.
悲しいときも寂しいときも信じ合えるものがある
Even when sad or lonely, there is something we can believe in together.
忘れずにこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい
I want to keep this heartbeat ringing without forgetting.
終わらない世界に溢れ出る笑顔達
Smiles overflowing in an endless world,
憧れの舞台立ちたいらしく輝きたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams and shine in my own way.
時に涙してまた笑い合いたい
Sometimes shedding tears, and smiling together once again.
同じ未来を見たいあの夢手にしたい
I want to see the same future, I want to make that dream mine.
踏み出そう奇跡の一歩を
Let's take that miraculous first step forward.
息切らしで夢追いかけたいワクワク止まらない
Gasping for breath as I chase my dreams, the excitement won't stop.
想像越えてく世界見せてあげるアクセスしてみたい？
I'll show you a world that surpasses imagination—want to try accessing it?
後悔なんてここにないそれぞれ違ったココロで作るworld
There's no room for regrets here, a world created by our different hearts.
いつも聴こえるエールはここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers I always hear right here,
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
it makes me want to search for a new light once more.
君の笑顔は保存して進む悲しいときに読み返すよ
Saving your smile as I move forward, I'll look back at it when I'm sad,
力が湧くから胸張って夢追いかけたい
because it gives me strength; I want to hold my head high and chase my dreams.
奇跡のストーリー一緒に作ろう
Let's create a miraculous story together.
終わらない夢を誰一人欠かせない
An endless dream where not a single person can be missed.
愛が舞ったこの世界それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
In this world where love danced, color it with our different hearts.
悲しいときも寂しいときも信じ合えるものがある
Even when sad or lonely, there is something we can believe in together.
忘れずにこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい
I want to keep this heartbeat ringing without forgetting.
終わらない世界に溢れ出る笑顔達
Smiles overflowing in an endless world,
憧れの舞台立ちたいらしく輝きたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams and shine in my own way.
時に涙してまた笑い合いたい
Sometimes shedding tears, and smiling together once again.
同じ未来を見たいあの夢手にしたい
I want to see the same future, I want to make that dream mine.
踏み出そう奇跡の一歩を
Let's take that miraculous first step forward.
息切らしで夢追いかけたいワクワク止まらない
Gasping for breath as I chase my dreams, the excitement won't stop.
想像越えてく世界見せてあげるそれぞれの違ったココロで
I'll show you a world that surpasses imagination, with our different hearts
彩れ
coloring it all.
かない世界に
In an unprecedented world...
あふれ出すよ 笑顔がしー
Overflowing with smiles!
-
あこがれの舞台に立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams,
らしく輝きたい
Looking radiant and brilliant,
ときに涙して
Tears welling up at times,
また笑い合いたい
Wanting to laugh together again.
同じ未来を見たい
Wanting to see the same future,
あの夢を手にしたい
Wanting to hold that dream close.
踏み出そう 奇跡の一歩を
Taking that first step into a miraculous world.
息ききらして 夢追いかけて
Breathing it all in, chasing my dreams,
ワクワク止まらない
My excitement just won't stop!
外側を越えてく 世界見せてあげる
Pushing past all boundaries, showing the world!
アクセスしてみてみない
Why not try a little access?
後悔なんてここにない
There's no regret here.
それぞれ違った 心で作るわ
Let's create our own unique hearts!
-